Alexandria, Egypt. 391 A.D. The World Changed Forever.
Agora is a adventure, drama, history film directed by Alejandro Amenábar.
A historical drama set in Roman Egypt, concerning philosopher Hypatia of Alexandria and her relationship with her slave Davus, who is
torn between his love for her and the possibility of gaining his freedom by joining the rising tide of Christianity.
Hypatia, played by Rachel Weisz.
Davus, played by Max Minghella.
Orestes, played by Oscar Isaac.
Ammonius, played by Ashraf Barhom.
Theon, played by Michael Lonsdale.
Synesius, played by Rupert Evans.
Agora (Spanish: Ágora) is a 2009 English-language Spanish historical drama film
directed by Alejandro Amenábar and written by Amenábar and Mateo Gil.
The biopic stars Rachel Weisz as Hypatia, a mathematician, philosopher and astronomer in late 4th-century Roman
Egypt, who investigates the flaws of the geocentric model, and the heliocentric model that challenges it.
Surrounded by religious turmoil and social unrest, Hypatia struggles to
save the knowledge of classical antiquity from destruction.
Max Minghella co-stars as Davus, Hypatia's father's slave, and Oscar Isaac
as Hypatia's student, and later prefect of Egypt, Orestes.
The story uses historical fiction to highlight the relationship between religion and science at the time
amidst the decline of Greco-Roman polytheism and the Christianization of the Roman Empire.
The title of the film takes its name from the agora, a public gathering
place in ancient Greece, similar to the Roman forum.
The film was produced by Fernando Bovaira and shot on the
island of Malta from March to June 2008.
Justin Pollard, co-author of The Rise and Fall of Alexandria
(2007), was the historical adviser for the film.
Agora was included in the official selection at the 2009 Cannes
Film Festival, but screened out of competition.
It opened in Spain on 9 October 2009 becoming the
highest-grossing film of the year for that country.
Although the film had difficulty finding distribution, it was released
country by country throughout late 2009 and early 2010.
The film received a 53% overall approval rating from Rotten Tomatoes and
seven Goya Awards in Spain, including Best Original Screenplay.
It was awarded the Alfred P.
Sloan Foundation Feature Film Prize at the Hamptons International Film Festival.
The film explores themes of egypt, new love, roman
empire, christianity, philosophy.
The tone is emotional.